Guide to the Sallie Bingham Papers, 1900-2023 and undated RL.00112
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1953-1998 and undated
  - Last Dance, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Laughing Cavalier, undated (Box 7)
  - Lawing, ca. 1979
    - Draft, Lawing.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 7)
  - Lent Poems, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Leonard Banks, undated
    - Drafts, Banks.doc, 1996, on Disk015, Disk023 and Disk024 (Box 7)
  - Letters to an Unknown Man (genesis of Upstate), 1975 (1 folder) (Box 7)
  - Letting Go, undated (Box 7)
  - Lies for the Living, undated (Box 7)
  - Lincoln, ca. 1985 (Box 7)
  - The List, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Little Miss X, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Little Queen, 1996
    - Draft, Queen.doc, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 7)
  - Living Abroad, early 1960s
    - Draft, Abroad.doc, 1996, on Disk023 (Box 7)
  - Lovers, 1984-1986 (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Lovers II, ca. 1986 (1 folder) (Box 8)
    - Productions, 1984, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Loving Julia, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Luke, ca. 1956 (Box 8)
  - Lyrics and Music, undated and 1988, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Mabel and Mrs. Muncie, 1992
    - Draft, Mabel.ss, 1997, on Disk024 (Box 8)
  - The Mad Woman, 1972
    - Draft, Madwom~1.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 8)
  - Making a Date for a Wedding, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Making a Fire, 1992 (4 folders; poetry) (Box 8)
  - Making Mischief, 1988 (Box 8)
  - A Man's Voice Offstage, undated (Box 8)
  - Mary, 1986 (production folder) (Box 8)
  - The Matron of Honor, 1980 (2 folders)
    - Draft, undated (5 folders) (Box 8)
    - Chapter five, undated (Box 8)
    - Edits to restore, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Jacket copy, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Outline ( 1981) and notes ( undated) (Box 8)
    - Publicity, reviews and correspondence, 1985-1998 (Box 8)
  - Mending, 1976
    - Draft, Mending.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 8)
  - Milk of Paradise, ca. 1979 (3 folders)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 8)
    - Draft, 1980 (1 folder) (Box 8)
    - Photographs, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Production file, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Publicity, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Published version, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Minor Characters, undated (2 folders)
    - Drafts, Minorcha.doc, 1996 (on Disk019), minor.doc, 1996 (on Disk023), Minor.doc, 1996 (on Disk024), and Oldhouse.doc, 1996 (on Disk024) (Box 9)
  - Miserable Offenders, 1985
    - Draft, Miserable.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 9)
  - Miss Thrush at Home, ca. 1958 (Box 9)
  - Modern Times, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Mother of all Battles, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Mothers, undated (Box 9)
  - Mourning, undated (Box 9)
  - Moving Day, 1961 (Box 9)
  - Murder, 1990 (Box 9)
  - My Mother's Clothes, ca. 1993-1995
    - Draft, Clothes.doc, 1996, on Disk023 (Box 9)
  - Nation (genesis of The Candidate's Lady and The Candidate's Wife), 1992 (3 folders)
    - Draft, 1994 (1 folder) (Box 9)
    - Notes, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Negative Capability, undated (poetry) (Box 9)
  - A New Life, 1972 (Box 9)
  - The New Place, 1965
    - Draft, Newpla~1.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 9)
  - Nick of Time, 1995 (3 folders)
    - Carolyn Krupp, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
    - Draft, 1996 (4 folders) (Box 9)
    - Drafts, Nick, 1996 (on Disk009) and Nick.doc, 1997 (on Disk021) (Box 9)
    - Draft and notes, Nick, undated, on Disk010 (Box 9)
    - Handwritten draft, 1996 (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Research and notes, 1996-1997 (Box 10)
    - Rewrites, 1997 (Box 10)
    - Title page with quote, Nik-titl.doc, 1997, on Disk021 (Box 10)
  - 1954, 1985 (Box 10)
  - No Time, 1988, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Noblesse Oblige, undated
    - Draft, noblesse.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 10)
  - Off Season, ca. 1990
    - Draft, season.doc, 1997, on Disk018 (Box 10)
    - Title page, Tit.off, 1997, on Disk018 (Box 10)
  - Oh Beautiful City of Dreams, 1997 (Box 10)
  - O'Keeffe (in electronic format only), 1996
    - Drafts, O'keeffe, 1996, on Disk009 and Disk014 (Box 10)
  - The Omen, undated (Box 10)
  - On Being a Feminist Mother, 1989 (Box 10)
  - On Being Sick in Bed, undated (Box 10)
  - On Loss, 1995 (Box 10)
  - On the Hercules, undated
    - Draft, hercules.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 10)
  - On Not Wanting and then Wanting Babies, undated (Box 10)
  - The Orange Juice King, 1994-1995
    - Drafts, Orange.s, 1994 (on Disk015) and Orange.ss, 1995 (on Disk009) (Box 10)
  - Our Lady or Happiness (genesis of The Postcard Collector), 1989 (5 folders)
    - Draft, 1990 (3 folders) (Box 10)
    - Draft, 1991-1992 (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Draft, undated (6 folders) (Box 10)
    - Draft, undated (4 folders) (Box 11)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 11)
    - Notes, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - Notes, Ourlady.not and Question.hd, undated, on Disk009 (Box 11)
    - Notes and part 2, chapters 3-11, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Notes, chapters 1 and 5, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - Part 2, chapters 12-17; part 3, chapters 1-6, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Part 2, chapters 3-9, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Parts 3 and 4, 1991-1992 (Box 11)
  - Paducah, undated (1 folder)
    - Draft, 1984 (1 folder) (Box 11)
    - Draft, 1985 (1 folder) (Box 11)
    - Photographs, 1985 (Box 11)
    - Publicity file, 1985 (Box 11)
    - Production file, 1985 (Box 11)
  - Parade, 1995/1996
    - Draft, Parade.ss, undated, on Disk009 (Box 11)
  - Parties, undated (Box 11)
  - Passion and Prejudice
    - Applause Books, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - Chapter notes and changes, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Chapter summary, undated, (1 folder) (Box 11)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 11)
    - Draft, 1988 (5 folders) (Box 11)
    - Draft, 1988 (13 folders) (Box 12)
    - Draft, undated (5 folders) (Box 12)
    - Draft, undated (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - Film interests, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - Final corrections, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Galleys, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Helen Merrill, 1986-1990 (Box 13)
    - Kate Seitz, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
    - Knopf contract, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Lynn Goldberg, 1988-1989 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 13)
    - New pages, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1988-1990 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, 1987 and 1989 (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - Outline, notes, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Permissions to publish, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Preface to Applause Books edition, 1990 (Box 13)
    - Proofs, 1988 (5 folders) (Box 13)
    - Proofs, 1988 (4 folders) (Box 14)
    - Publicity, 1988 (Box 14)
    - Publisher's final draft, 1988 (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Publisher's final draft, 1988 (4 folders) (Box 14)
    - Publisher's job specifications, 1988 (1 folder) (Box 14)
    - Research files, undated (8 folders) (Box 14)
    - Research files, undated (14 folders) (Box 15)
    - Response of Bingham family, 1989 (Box 15)
    - Response to Hayney's cartoon, 1989 (Box 15)
    - Response to So-called Errors and Mistatements, 1989 (Box 15)
    - Royalties, 1989-1993 (Box 15)
    - Shirley Williams libel suit, 1989 (Box 15)
    - Summary response document, 1988 (Box 15)
    - Supporting material in answer to questions raised by attorney, 1988-1989 (Box 15)
  - Perfect Balls: Patriotism, Subversion and the Male Myth, undated (Box 15)
  - Persephone in Night Town, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Piggyback, undated (2 folders)
    - Additional scenes, publicity, correspondence, 1987-1994 (Box 15)
    - Draft, Piggybac, 1995, on Disk023 (Box 15)
  - The Pin (in electronic format only), 1997
    - Draft, Pin~1.doc, 1997, on Disk024 (Box 15)
  - Pirate Gold, 1988 (Box 15)
  - A Place in the Country, 1974 (Box 15)
  - Please No Eating or Drinking, undated (Box 15)
  - Pleyben, ca. 1980s
    - Drafts, Pleyben.doc, 1996 (on Disk023 and Disk024) and 1997 (on Disk019) (Box 15)
  - Politics, undated (Box 15)
  - Porn, undated and 1995/1996
    - Drafts, Porn.ss, undated (on Disk009) and Porn, 1995 (on Disk024) (Box 15)
  - The Postcard Collector, 1990 (1 folder)
    - Draft, 1990 (3 folders) (Box 16)
    - Notes, miscellaneous chapters, 1992 (Box 16)
    - Quote, Pc.quo, undated, on Disk009 (Box 16)
  - Post-modern White Bread, undated
    - Draft, Postmod.ss, 1997, on Disk024 (Box 16)
  - The Price of Innocence, 1995 (6 folders)
    - Cast list and notes, Notes, 1993, on Disk013 (Box 16)
    - Draft, undated (6 folders) (Box 16)
    - Draft, undated (3 folders) (Box 17)
    - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 17)
    - List of chapters, Disk4_1.doc, 1993, on Disk011 (Box 17)
    - Drafts of miscellaneous chapters, 1993-1995, on Disk002, Disk004, Disk005, Disk011, Disk012 and Disk013 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous chapters, undated (1 folder) (Box 17)
    - Notes, 1987-1995 (Box 17)
    - Notes, Disk4_4.doc, 1993 (on Disk011) and Notes, 1995 (on Disk004) (Box 17)
    - Notes on time scheme, Disk4_2.doc and Disk4_3.doc, 1993, on Disk011 (Box 17)
    - Questions for second draft, Disk2_9.doc, 1993, on Disk011 (Box 17)
    - Quotes, Dedi.pri, 1993 (on Disk005) and Quote, 1995 (on Disk004) (Box 17)
    - Title page, Title, 1997, on Disk004 (Box 17)
  - A Private Landscape, 1980s (Box 17)
  - Rachel's Island, 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Reading the Greeks, 1994
    - Drafts, Greeks.ss, 1996, on Disk019 and Disk024 (Box 17)
  - The Realtor, 1991 (Box 17)
  - The Red Car, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Relations, undated (Box 17)
  - Remembering, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Reunion, 1980s
    - Draft, Reunion.doc, 1994, on Disk024 (Box 17)
  - Revenant, 1970s (Box 17)
  - Rich Women Lose When They Play by the Rules, 1986 (Box 17)
  - The Riding Lessons, undated (Box 17)
  - River's Edge, undated (Box 17)
  - Robin, undated (Box 17)
  - The Root of the Tree, 1980s (Box 17)
  - Sagesse, undated
    - Draft, Sagesse, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 17)
  - Santa Fe Days, undated
    - Draft, Santafe, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 17)
    - Notes, Santafe.ide, undated, on Disk009 (Box 17)
  - Santa Fe: Prodigal Daughter, 1995 (2 folders)
    - Drafts, Santafe, 1995, on Disk006 and Disk010 (Box 17)
  - Santa Fe Style, 1997
    - Draft, Sfstyle.sto, 1997, on Disk018 (Box 17)
  - Settling Scores, undated (Box 17)
  - Shall We Dance? 1997 (Box 17)
  - The Shot Tower (in electronic format only), 1996
    - Draft, Shottowe.s, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 17)
  - Shredding the Flag, 1992 (Box 17)
  - Skal, Skal, Ikke, 1977 (Box 17)
  - Small Victories, undated (1 folder)
    - Draft, undated (1 folder) (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1998 (Box 18)
    - Publicity, Reviews, 1989-1992 (Box 18)
    - Royalties, 1993-1996 (Box 18)
    - Zoland Books contract, 1991 (Box 18)
  - Snake Goddess, undated (Box 18)
  - Snow on the Coal, 1983 (Box 18)
  - Snow on the Coal, Subdivision, Ohio River Winter, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Solo, undated (4 folders) (Box 18)
  - Sons in Law, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Southern Women Writers, 1992 (Box 18)
  - A Southerner in New York, undated (Box 18)
  - Southernmost Point, undated (3 folders)
    - 1992 (1 folder) (Box 18)
  - Spoletto Poems, 1994 (Box 18)
  - Stealing the Bees, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Stealing the Spirit, ca. 1990 (Box 18)
  - Stove Heart, ca. 1991 (Box 18)
  - Straight Man, undated (2 folders)
    - Draft, 1979 (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1997 (Box 19)
    - Inserts and notes, 1995 (Box 19)
    - Notes, Straight.bk!, and Straight.not, undated, on Disk009 (Box 19)
    - Publicity, 1996 (Box 19)
    - Royalties, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Summary, Straight.sum, undated, on Disk009 (Box 19)
  - Summer Plans, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Sundagger, undated
    - Draft and note, Sundagge.ss, 1997, on Disk024 (Box 19)
  - Swings, 1985-1995
    - Drafts, Swing.ss, 1995 (on Disk024) and Swings.doc, 1996 (on Disk019) (Box 19)
  - The Tease, 1997
    - Draft, Tease, 1997, on Disk024 (Box 19)
  - The Texture of Happiness, 1997
    - Draft, Happy, 1996, on Disk015 (Box 19)
  - Things that Go, undated
    - Draft, Things~1.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 19)
  - This Land Was Ours Before We Were the Land's, 1990 (Box 19)
  - This Simple Faith, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Throw Away, undated (2 folders) (Box 19)
  - Thunder Thy Clarion, undated and 1995/1996
    - Drafts, Thunder.ss, 1995, on Disk009 and Disk024 (Box 19)
  - The Tin Man, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Tiny Queen (in electronic format only), 1977
    - Draft, Queenw~1.doc, 1997, on Disk020 (Box 19)
  - The Touching Hand, draft, 1965 (1 folder)
    - Draft, 1967 (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Proofs, 1967 (1 folder) (Box 19)
    - Reviews, Contract, Correspondence, 1967 (Box 19)
    - Uncorrected Proofs, 1967 (1 folder) (Box 19)
  - Traveller, undated (Box 19)
  - Tribute to Angels, undated (poetry) (Box 19)
  - Truchas Tales, 1994
    - Draft, Truchas.ss, 1996, on Disk024 (Box 19)
  - The Truth About Growing Up Rich, 1986 (Box 19)
  - Turn a Deaf Ear, 1975 (Box 19)
  - The Unearthing of True Desire (in electronic format only), 1997
    - Title page and note, Flan.tit, 1997, on Disk024 (Box 19)
  - Unmarrying, 1990 (Box 19)
  - Upstate, undated (2 folders)
    - Aftermath and notes, undated and 1992 (Box 19)
    - Corrections, 1993 (Box 19)
    - Draft, 1993 (1 folder) (Box 19)
    - Permanent Press contract and correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 19)
    - Published book, 1993 (Box 19)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1992-1993 (Box 19)
    - Royalties, 1993 (Box 19)
  - The Visit, undated (Box 19)
  - To Wake from Dreaming, 1974 (Box 19)
  - A Walk, 1985 (Box 19)
  - The Wall Between, ca. 1982 (1 folder)
    - Draft, ca. 1982 (1 folder) (Box 20)
    - Draft, ca. 1982-1983 (1 folder) (Box 20)
    - Draft, ca. 1983 (1 folder) (Box 20)
    - Production and publicity, 1983 (Box 20)
  - The Wandering Eye, 1988 (Box 20)
  - War Time, ca. 1995 (poetry)
    - Notes on awards and publications, Acknow, 1996, on Disk007 (Box 20)
    - Table of contents, Contents, 1996, on Disk007 (Box 20)
    - Title page, Title, 1996, on Disk007 (Box 20)
  - The Way it is Now, 1971 (2 folders)
    - Draft, undated (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - Galleys, 1971 (Box 20)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1972 (Box 20)
    - Publicity, 1972 (Box 20)
    - Viking Contract, 1971, 1986 (Box 20)
  - We are Powerless, 1990
    - Draft, Powerles, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 20)
  - The Weary Wayfarer, 1982 (Box 20)
  - The Wedding, undated (Box 20)
  - West, 1990 (Box 20)
  - Where are the Women? undated (Box 20)
  - Why I Owned a Pistol, 1994 (Box 20)
  - The Widower, 1985
    - Draft, Widower.doc, 1996, on Disk019 (Box 20)
  - The Wild Man of Borneo, 1994
    - Drafts, Borneo.ss and Borneo2, 1994, on Disk015 (Box 20)
  - Wild Things, 1990
    - Draft, Wild, 1995, on Disk024 (Box 20)
  - A Winter Marriage, 1956 (2 folders) (Box 20)
  - Winter Term, 1957 (Box 20)
  - The Wolf Hunt, 1997 (Box 20)
  - Woman, Get Up, undated (Box 20)
  - A Woman's Land, undated (Box 20)
  - Women Beware Women, undated (Box 20)
  - Words in the Language, 1981 (1 folder)
    - Draft, 1993 (1 folder) (Box 20)
    - Draft, Words.doc, 1996, on Disk017 (Box 20)
    - Draft, undated (2 folders) (Box 20)
  - The Young Girls, 1955 (Box 20)
  - The Young Husband, 1988
    - Drafts, Husband, 1996 (on Disk014) and 1997 (on Disk024) (Box 20)
  - The Young Husband and Other Stories (in electronic format only), 1995
    - Title page, Title, 1995, on Disk024 (Box 20)
  - Zephyr Catalogue Introduction, undated (Box 21)
  - Book reviews written by Bingham, undated (Box 21)
  - Guest editor and reviews for The American Book Review, 1989, 1993 (Box 21)
  - Letters to the Editor, ca. 1985-1997 (Box 21)
  - The Louisville Courier-Journal book page columns, 1984-1985 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous (ideas, fragments, notes), undated (2 folders) (Box 21)
  - Newspaper clippings for research, 1988-1997 (Box 21)
  - Plays produced by Bingham, Plays, 1995, on Disk023 (Box 21)
  - Projects proposed to Zoland Books, 1992-1997 (Box 21)
  - Proposed Projects
    - Anais and Henry, 1990 (Box 21)
    - Austin Caperton Brown, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Carrie Nation, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Grimke sisters, 1989 (Box 21)
    - Kentucky women, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Lady Mary Wortley Montague, 1995 (Box 21)
    - Mata Hari, 1991 (Box 21)
    - McCredie project, 1990 (Box 21)
    - Over there: American women in London during WWII, 1995 (Box 21)
    - Willa Elam, 1987-1991 (Box 21)
    - Women and madness, 1988-1990 (Box 21)
  - Published works (list of poems, essays and short stories), Acknowle, 1997, on Disk008 (Box 21)
  - Submissions to writing contests in 1995 and 1996, Submissi, 1996, on Disk008 (Box 21)
  - Writings (in progress), ca. 1980s (Box 21)
- Oversize Materials, undated
  Oversize materials separated from various series in the main collection. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Subject Files Series (Box 1)
    - Articles about and interviews with Bingham (Box 1)
    - Drawings of Bingham (Box 1)
    - Radcliffe diploma (Box 1)
    - Readings (posters) (Box 1)
  - Writings Series
    - The Awakening (publicity) (Box 1)
    - Fear (published in Nova, 1972) (Box 1)
    - Hopscotch (costume sketches) (Box 1)
    - Passion and Prejudice
      - The Paperdoll (Box 1)
      - Publicity (Box 1)
      - Research maps of North Carolina (Box 1)
    - Rachel's Island (published in Nova, 1972) (Box 1)
    - To Wake from Dreaming (published in Chatelaine, 1974) (Box 1)
  - Photographs Series (RESTRICTED) (Box 2)
    - Arthur Caperton (Box 2)
    - Jonathan Worth Bingham scrapbook, ca. 1950s (Box 2)
    - Photographs used in Passion and Prejudice (Box 2)
  - The Kentucky Foundation for Women Series (RESTRICTED)
    - Wolf Pen Farm maps (Box 2)
- Accession (1992-052) 1958-1990, 2 boxes
  Access to this series is restricted. Patrons must request permission from the donor for access.
  - Notebooks and daybooks (Box 1)
  - Photo album (Box 1)
  - Videocassette (Box 1)
  - 2 pinback buttons (Box 1)
  - Notebooks (Box 2)
- Accession (1999-0238) 1996-1999
  - Articles on me (Box 1)
  - Awards, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Going Native (Box 1)
  - Jeff Co, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Raggle Taggle Gypsies (Box 1)
  - The Pin (Box 1)
  - Pleyben (Box 1)
  - Minor Characters (Box 1)
  - The Iron Age (Box 1)
  - Wolf Pen (Box 1)
  - Santa Fe Style 4/1997 (Box 1)
  - Poems from War Time (Box 1)
  - Short stories, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Book jacket photo (Box 1)
  - Craig, 7/21/1998 (Box 1)
  - Craig, 7/30/1998 (Box 1)
  - Craig fax, 8/4/1998 (Box 1)
  - Craig, 8/10/1998 (Box 1)
  - Craig, 10/1998 (Box 1)
  - Craig, 10/1998 (Box 1)
  - Craig, 10/22/1998 (Box 1)
  - Craig, 10/19/1998 (Box 1)
  - Craig, 7/15/1998 (Box 1)
  - Wild Animals I Have Known, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Mayor's Award (Box 1)
  - Blind Love (Box 1)
  - Deadlines, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Going Native, typescript of draft (Box 1)
  - Writings (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Clippings and awards (Box 1)
- Accession (2000-0010), 1960-1999
  Addition (2000-0010) (250 items, .20 linear feet, dated 1960-1999) comprises correspondence, including letters of thanks, further documenting Bingham's identity as a philanthropist and advocate of women writers. Also includes clippings, especially regarding the death of Robert Bingham; photographs; and a few handwritten poems. There is no container list for this accession.
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Snapshots, 1960s-1970s (Box 1)
- Accession (2000-0210)--RESTRICTED, 2 boxes
  Addition (2000-0210) (1050 items, 1.70 linear feet, dated 1985-2000) contains professional and personal correspondence, writings, photographs, clippings, legal papers, and other materials. Writings include typescripts of short stories, nineteen of which have were published as GOING NATIVE; holograph poems; typescripts of the novel, The Price of Innocence; and memoirs. Other materials relate to Bingham's connection with Santa Fe Stages, publishing, her family, and personal life.
  Patrons must request permission from the donor for access to personal information. These restricted documents have been moved to the end of box 1 and to box 2. The manuscripts and printed material in the beginning of box 1 are open for research.
  - Open for research
    - Readup file (Box 1)
    - First Drafts-Poems/Works 2000 (Box 1)
    - Southwest Review (Box 1)
    - First Drafts-Poems 1999-2000 (Box 1)
    - Rob Bingham 2000 (Box 1)
    - Going Native (1998 Collection, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous 1999 (Box 1)
    - How the South Won (Bingham 2000 March) (Box 1)
    - News Stories 2000 (Box 1)
    - Sylvia (Bingham; short story 2000) (Box 1)
    - Envelope containing various correspondence (Box 1)
    - No Time (Bingham) (Box 1)
    - The Hub of the Miracle (Bingham; poems) (Box 1)
    - Second Draft: Hub of the Miracle (1999 December) (Box 1)
    - First Draft: Hub of the Miracle (1999 December) (Box 1)
    - Love and Me: An Erotic Memoir (Bingham 1999), 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Royalties 1999-2000 (Box 1)
    - Manuscript, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous 1998-1999 (Box 1)
      (incl. 2 photos)
    - Awards 1999 (Box 1)
    - Craft (Bingham 1996 August 30) (Box 1)
    - Acknowledgements-Poetry (Box 1)
    - Art (Bingham 1997) (Box 1)
    - In Boston (Bingham [ca. 1970s]) (Box 1)
    - Captain Bud (Bingham 1985) (Box 1)
    - The Eyes of Addicts (Bingham; manuscript) (Box 1)
    - Zoland Books (Box 1)
    - Southwest Review (story acceptance) (Box 1)
    - TheaterWork (Box 1)
    - Essays (Box 1)
    - Janice Sevre-Duszynska (Box 1)
    - Morris Grubbs Collection (Box 1)
    - I Am the Resurrection and the Life (Bingham) (Box 1)
    - Lawing (Bingham [ca. 1980s]) (Box 1)
    - South by Southwest Index (Box 1)
    - Wild Animals I Have... (Bingham) (Box 1)
    - Wartime (Bingham; poems) (Box 1)
    - Georgetown Review (Box 1)
    - Santa Fe Style 1999 (Box 1)
    - Published stories (Box 1)
    - May the Circle (Box 1)
    - New poems 1998 (Box 1)
    - Book Reviews (Box 1)
    - Country Western (Bingham 1999) (Box 1)
    - Summer 2000 Schedule (Box 1)
    - Playwriting Women: 7 Plays from the Women's Project (Box 1)
    - 1999 WKU Fall Commencement (video, 1999 December 18) (Box 1)
  - Restricted
    - Letters 2000 (Box 1)
    - 716 Acequia Madre (Box 1)
      (incl. approx. 20 photos)
    - Literary Executor [?] (Box 1)
    - Nieh-Nat's Letter (Box 1)
    - Ellsworth Divorce 1965 (Box 1)
    - Photos (Box 1)
    - Wolf Pen Farm 2000 (Box 1)
    - Iovenko Divorce 1979 (Box 1)
    - TAV: History (restricted) (Box 1)
    - KFW: History (restricted) (Box 1)
    - Agent's, 1997 March (Box 2)
    - Kentucky Foundation for Women (Box 2)
    - Judy Chicago (Box 2)
    - Sarah Gorhaw [?] (Box 2)
    - La Alameda Press (Box 2)
    - Letters to Save (1998) (Box 2)
    - Mary Ellen Miller (1998) (Box 2)
    - Nick of Time, Sarah's letter (Box 2)
    - Susan Schulman (Box 2)
    - Astrology (1999 January 21; cassette tape) (Box 2)
    - Miscellany (envelope) (Box 2)
- Accession (2000-0259)--RESTRICTED, 2 boxes
  Addition (2000-0259) (367 items, 1.90 linear feet, dated 1941-1999) contains personal rather than professional documents, especially 17 diaries and journals. Also included are letters, writings, school reports, and photographs (1940s) kept by Bingham's mother, Mary Caperton Bingham; and legal papers, clippings, and other materials compiled by Bingham about family and business matters, including her mother's death.
  Patrons must secure permission from donor for access to materials that contain personal information.
  - Letters from Sallie to Eleanor Box (folders marked with an 'A') (Box 1)
    Miscellaneous correspondence (including a letter from Adlai Stephenson), photographs, printed items, cards made by children, letters from Bingham to family, poems and short writings, a lock of Bingham's hair, some items related to Sarah Bingham's wedding, and Sallie Bingham's time at Radcliffe.
  - Sallie, 1985-1991 and Records-Children (folders marked with a 'B') (Box 1)
    Materials related to the death of Bingham's mother, Mary, and Sallie Bingham's divorce.
  - Diaries (Box 1)
  - Diaries (Box 2)
- Accession (2000-0364), 1991-2000, 2 boxes